<speak><prosody pitch="13.77922%" rate="2.51948%">This is the story about the color monster</prosody></speak><speak><prosody pitch="-15.13841%" rate="-10.27682%"> Today he woke up feeling confused, and he does not know why</prosody></speak><speak><prosody pitch="-13.23806%" rate="-6.47612%"> Are you all mixed up again, Color Monster? Your emotions do not work well when they are all jumbled up</prosody></speak><speak><prosody pitch="-16.83882%" rate="-13.67764%"> You should try to separate them, and put each one in its own jar</prosody></speak><speak><prosody pitch="14.488135%" rate="2.99209%"> If you like, I can help you with that</prosody></speak><speak><prosody pitch="17.25673%" rate="4.83782%"> Lets try to make sense of how you feel</prosody></speak><speak><prosody pitch="24.90493%" rate="9.936620000000001%"> I am going to start describing the happiness</prosody></speak><speak><prosody pitch="24.043525000000002%" rate="9.362350000000001%"> It shines yellow like the Sun and twinkles like the Stars</prosody></speak><speak><prosody pitch="20.442835%" rate="6.9618899999999995%"> When you are happy, you jump and dance and play and laugh: ahh ha ha ha! You want to share your happiness with everyone! Ok, I you have it clear, we will continue exploring another one, the sadness</prosody></speak><speak><prosody pitch="-13.06521%" rate="-6.13042%"> It is lonely and blue like a rainy day it washes over you like the sea</prosody></speak><speak><prosody pitch="-19.43367%" rate="-18.86734%"> When you are sad you hide and want to be alone</prosody></speak><speak><prosody pitch="-18.01181%" rate="-16.02362%"> You do not want to do anything except maybe cry: snif snif</prosody></speak><speak><prosody pitch="24.102025%" rate="9.40135%"> Finally, and this is the last one, the calm</prosody></speak><speak><prosody pitch="14.181715%" rate="2.78781%"> It is quiet like the trees and as light as the green leaves swaying in the wind</prosody></speak><speak><prosody pitch="15.347010000000001%" rate="-20.694020000000002%"> When you are calm, you breathe slowly and deeply</prosody></speak><speak><prosody pitch="20.859595%" rate="7.23973%"> You feel at peace</prosody></speak><speak><prosody pitch="-14.84127%" rate="-9.68254%"> Now you can rest, Color Monster! All your feelings are in the right place</prosody></speak><speak><prosody pitch="17.165305%" rate="4.77687%"> I hope you have learned to differentiate between the diferent emotions! Do not you feel much better?
</prosody></speak>