<speak><prosody pitch="-13.85745%" rate="-7.7149%">I rejected the idea of living separate lifes</prosody></speak><speak><prosody pitch="-19.66365%" rate="-19.3273%"> Sincerely, I could not stand it anymore, I felt tired of crying all the time, I could not remain hidden</prosody></speak><speak><prosody pitch="16.78644%" rate="-23.57288%"> Thus, I took courage to go to his home and, sweating intensely I ringed the doorbell ding-dong</prosody></speak><speak><prosody pitch="-7.92268%" rate="6.03866%"> Nothing! I heavily insisted but it did not make any noise</prosody></speak><speak><prosody pitch="-16.24281%" rate="-12.485619999999999%"> Obviously, it was broken</prosody></speak><speak><prosody pitch="-2.8859900000000005%" rate="8.557005%"> I had no choice but to harm my knuckles knocking the door knock knock and suddenly, the door blade opened</prosody></speak><speak><prosody pitch="18.8065%" rate="-27.613%"> I closed my eyes before saying hello with a scared and trembling voice</prosody></speak><speak><prosody pitch="20.89888%" rate="7.26592%"> And I felt a kiss in my red, soft and full lips</prosody></speak><speak><prosody pitch="-13.60258%" rate="-7.20516%"> Oh Lord, what a disappointment, what a strong deception! I was gifted with a boring, dull and tasteless kiss! where were the butterflies in the stomach? where the timeless sensation? the thirst for more? No words were needed</prosody></speak><speak><prosody pitch="-16.08478%" rate="-12.169559999999999%"> It was time to open my eyes and realize that I was free finally</prosody></speak><speak><prosody pitch="-16.83654%" rate="-13.673079999999999%"> I barely looked to his head, made half turn and walked towards the exit</prosody></speak><speak><prosody pitch="-16.411949999999997%" rate="-12.823899999999998%"> For the first time I was able to breath deeply, to forget the emotional burden with which I had carried out on my shoulders and, shit, to be able to be happy again</prosody></speak><speak><prosody pitch="23.174259999999997%" rate="8.78284%"> I celebrated it with a cold, big and tasty beer in the first pub I found on my way home</prosody></speak>